Nicholas Lopes Laranjeiro

Hamilton, ON | nicholaslaranjeiro@hotmail.com | nicklaranjeiro.github.io | 905-979-9232

PERSONAL STATEMENT

With over 2+ years experience as a full stack developer and freelance mentor for React and Angular, I push best practices into my work and teachings alike. While keeping the bar high, I know this results in high quality code that is easier to maintain. I am looking for a permanent position in a professional environment after honing my skills working full-time as a full stack developer for Dealerpull, internships at ComQi and PHRI, and as a freelance code mentor where I maintain a 5 star rating with every client.

EDUCATION

3 Year Advanced Diploma | Mohawk College

Sep 2016 - Dec 2019

- Major: Computer Systems Technology Software Development
- Relevant courses: Emerging Web Technologies, HTML5 & Mobile Web Development, Data Structures & Algorithms, Web Applications ASP.NET, Database Theory, Secure Software

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer | Dealerpull | Kitchener, ON

Mar 2021 - Present

- Developed, implemented and supported overall web architecture for a multi-tenant SaaS platform
- Designed and constrcuted a REST API, integrating the front-end user interface along with it
- Upgraded existing codebase in order to improve the performance, design, stability and security
- Communicated with the business teams in order to ensure the technical solutions met business requirements and needs

Freelance Developer | Codementor | Hamilton, ON

Mar 2020 - Mar 2021

- Codementor is an online platform for developers to instantly connect with experts for one-on-one live help or long term mentorships to improve their coding skills and knowledge
- Collaborated with over 125 clients to resolve issues while enforcing high quality coding conventions
- Assessed and fixed client issues in React, Angular, HTML & CSS, JavaScript, PHP and SQL
- Awarded Codementor of the week 13 times for being a top performing mentor

Front End Software Developer Co-op | ComQi | Burlington, ON

May 2019 - Aug 2019

- Implemented front end software components for a cloud based content management solution
- Built a good understanding of how to write well documented quality code through code reviews
- Improved the efficiency and design of how customers uploaded media content to the application which was well received by the design team along with the customers
- Worked with the front end team to implement product designs, requirements, and produce high quality software

Full Stack Developer Co-op | PHRI | Hamilton, ON

Sep 2018 – Jan 2019

- Created full-stack ASP.NET web applications for large budget drug research management
- Using Agile methodology, worked closely with business analysts and other developers in scrums
- Programmed the web applications using C#, JavaScript, HTML & CSS, SQL
- Applied my knowledge of Object Oriented and .NET framework concepts to solve bugs and add needed features